Dr. Khalifa: Now this is, I mean, Satan cannot say that these people are, are mine.
He cannot say that.
When they say,
[60:4] ... "We disown you and the idols you worship beside GOD. We denounce you, and you will see nothing from us except animosity and hatred until you believe in GOD ALONE."* ...
And then, we're given the example of Abraham and his father.
[60:4] ... However, a mistake was committed by Abraham when he said to his father, "I will pray for your forgiveness,** but I possess no power to protect you from GOD." "Our Lord, we trust in You; we submit to You; to You is the final destiny.
[60:5] "Our Lord, let us not be oppressed by those who disbelieved, and forgive us. You are the Almighty, Most Wise."
So, I think we learn from this page that we just, our stand must be firm, and it reminds us that we are here.
All this trouble is because we rebelled, we did not make a firm stand on the side of God when the Great Feud happened.
The jinns, for example, made a firm stand with Satan, and we, we didn't.
We said "maybe, maybe, Satan can make it and be a god."
We did not make a firm stand with God.
So, this is our time to make up for it, and to denounce that wishy-washy stand that we had in the past.
Ok, verse 6.
[60:6] A good example has been set by them for those who seek GOD and the Last Day. As for those who turn away, GOD is in no need (of them), Most Praiseworthy.
[60:7] GOD may change the animosity between you and them into love. ...
You see, what I mean when I said make your firm, your stand known orally, publicly, and tell them
"it's ok, you can study and examine the evidence until God guides you.
But make it known.
[60:7] ... GOD is Omnipotent. GOD is Forgiver, Most Merciful.
And these relationships are regulated by the next two verses.
It tells you exactly how to behave towards whom.
Number 8 says,
[60:8] GOD does not enjoin you from befriending those who do not fight you because of religion, and do not evict you from your homes. You may befriend them and be equitable towards them. GOD loves the equitable.
So, these are not considered the enemies of God if they are not actively opposing you.
They may be curious. They may be still looking. They may be still examining the evidence.
You'll be able to tell if they are hostile or not.
Number 9 tells you that
[60:9] GOD enjoins you only from befriending those who fight you because of religion, evict you from your homes, and band together with others to banish you. You shall not befriend them. Those who befriend them are the transgressors.
Dr. Khalifa: If you are friends of somebody who's opposing God and His Messenger, what does this tell about you?
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: Wishy-washy.
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A man: Wishy-washy. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Or worse.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You have to make your stand very firm on the side of God alone.
If somebody is idolizing Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or some saint with God, you have to
make your stand known that you don't like that, that you are not their friends until
they abandon their idolatry and dedicate themselves to God alone.
Otherwise, we will be like them.
This is... throughout the Quran, we see this.
If you don't, if you don't do that, you are like them, as guilty as they are.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: Yeah. For example, you work in the same office for them and provided they don't follow you. You Pray own way.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: they pray their own way and they don't follow you.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. A man: They meet you in the same restaurant.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: You, you meet in the same clubs and all places, play the same game in a place in the evening. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Provided they follow you...
Dr. Khalifa: They don't bother you, they're not fighting you. Then,...
A man: Yeah, you can talk to them. A man: They're neutral.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Neutral. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They're neutral. There's still, there's still hope for them.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there's no problem you talk to them, you play around, joke with them, (unintelligible) aside? Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, verses 8 and 9 are really, are the rule that covers, the umbrella rule.
A man: Can we do (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: If they're still, if they're still neutral, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Especially, if it's going to help them.
A man: Surely, if they declare themselves, declare themselves that they are non-believers, can we do good to them?
Dr. Khalifa: No, you better run away from them.
Dr. Khalifa: If they declare themselves as non-believers, you better...
A man: If they need help, one kind or the other...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Help, some kind of, shall we help them?
Dr. Khalifa: Not if they declare themselves as unbelievers. They're enemies of God. Yes. A man: They have. They have.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you have to run, run away from them.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't help them. A man: Don't help them? Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what, let's read it again.
Number 9,
[60:9] GOD enjoins you from befriending those who fight you because of religion, evict you from your homes, and band together with others to banish you. ...
Better yet, if you look at verse number 1, it says,
[60:1] O you who believe, you shall not befriend My enemies and your enemies, ...
So, a person who declared himself as an unbeliever is an enemy of God.
It shows the opposite side.
Unless you have something else in mind as far as declare themselves unbelievers.
Dr. Khalifa: Can you be more specific?
Edip: For sure. I mean, excuse me.
Edip: How a person can be, can be included in number verse 8?
Edip: These are not believers, in fact.
Dr. Khalifa: But they're neutral. Edip: They are disbelievers.
Edip: And they are not actively fighting against believers. In the...
Edip: Because in number 8, there are some people that they are not believers, but they do not believe
or maybe they are agnostic, maybe they are Christian or Jews, they worship, but they have not animosity, how do you say, enmity.
Edip: They're (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: There's no fighting, in other words.
Edip: They don't fight.
Dr. Khalifa: Will this define what you mean?
A man: Exactly.
A man: Here, "extending love and friendship to them", but there is a, there is a wide margin between love and friendship.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: I personally as a good Muslim would like to love my enemy.
A man: I do not know whether that enemy is the enemy of God, but it says both, "your enemies and My enemies."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: But I am specifying that there is a person, I know that he's my enemy.
I wouldn't call anyone my enemy, but I would say that this man has done bad to me.
I would like to love him.
A man: I would respond by loving him.
Dr. Khalifa: Cause you're enemy like in work, there are circumstances. So,...
Dr. Khalifa: Unless he goes a little too far by, as it says that, take my house, take my home away,
A man: then of course, I would retaliate differently.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, if it is, if it is personal friction, the Quran actually tells you to love your enemy. A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, if it's a personal matter, like, for example, he built his fence A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: inside your territory instead of, you know, half yard inside your territory or something, this has nothing to do with God.
And in fact, I don't know if the Arabic will mean anything to you,
(28:54) يَدْرَءُونَ بِٱلْحَسَنَةِ ٱلسَّيِّئَةَ
In other words, if something does bad to you, you do good to them.
Perhaps he will become your friend in the future.
Dr. Khalifa: But here, we're talking strictly religion, as far as worshipping God alone is concerned.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, when you say "my enemy..."
A man: The ultimate would be that he may turn to be a believer, because I am a believer. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right, if you mean by "my enemy", personal animosity, that is, the Quran tells you to do good to them, to love your enemy.
But, because you'll be fighting for your sake, not for God's sake.
This is why the verse starts with "My enemies." God is saying "My enemies" first.
Dr. Khalifa: [60:1] ... you shall not befriend My enemies and your enemies, ...
Edip: The God's enemies also show our enemies.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
A woman: Because (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: So,
Dr. Khalifa: the love and hate should be for the sake of God, not for our personal sake.
Feroz: And these are not all idol worshippers, it's only the ones that are actively fighting.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You know, let us face it, when we grew up, they taught us idolatry, idol worship.
We grew up as idol worshippers, all of us, this generation anyway.
The new generation is cleaner than we are.
But, you give them a chance to see the truth.
So, if they're not fighting you, there is hope that someday they may be better than you and me.
A man: But... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: Yes, I was telling you, stay in the same office, you share the same restaurant and all these things,
and they are neutral, and they happen to be in need of some help.
A man: Now, won't you help them in such a situation?
Dr. Khalifa: You help them if they're not fighting you.
Dr. Khalifa: If they're not actively fighting you, you help them, yes.
A man: And in case, I mean, they need your help.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, look on them as potential believers. You're trying to woo them, actually. A man: Ok. Yeah.
A man: Ok. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: You can help them in such a situation. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: You can befriend them, help them.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what verse 8 is saying. It says,
[60:8] GOD does not prohibit you from befriending those who are not fighting you..., and not evicting you from your homes. ...
[60:8] ... fighting you because of religion, ...
Dr. Khalifa: Excuse me, I have to add those three words.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Because of religion, not because of personal matters.
A woman: Rashad, throughout the Quran, we see that we need that we should respect the relatives.
Dr. Khalifa: Regard, regard the relatives. A woman: Regard, regard the relatives.
A woman: And if one of our relatives is idol worshipper.
Dr. Khalifa: You disown them. No, no, excuse me, go on, "I'm fighting you." I'm sorry. Yes.
A woman: If they, if they declare that they believe in, they put Muhammad beside God. They declare... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But they are not fighting you.
A woman: But they are not fighting you. Dr. Khalifa: Fine, it's ok.
A woman: It's fine? Dr. Khalifa: You can be their friends and love them and everything and try, try to woo them to worshiping God alone.
A man: (31:15) وَإِن جَـٰهَدَاكَ Because
A man: (31:15) وَإِن جَـٰهَدَاكَ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: That time, there'll be problem.
Dr. Khalifa: (31:15) لَا تُطِعْهُمَا
Dr. Khalifa: They don't even fight you. A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This is about the parents.
A man: Only if they struggle against you.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. No, she's talking about relatives, like cousins, cousins, aunts, nephews, nieces. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Right?
A man: Even if your parents, if they fight you, you still have to respect them.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: But you don't, you don't obey them in that particular idol worshipping situation. A man: in that particular.
A woman: Is there any difference between which relatives that you're asking?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the parents have a special position.
Dr. Khalifa: The parents, God says "don't say 'Uff' to them."
A woman: Alright. But you say if they're idol worshipping, we should...
Dr. Khalifa: But, but God gives you permission to disobey them if they are forcing you to commit idolatry.
They say "you must mention Muhammad and Ibrahim in your Prayer", for example.
You don't obey them.
You say "ok, mom or dad, I just keep, I understand your opinion and I appreciate your situation, but I'll do it my way. It's my neck."
A woman: Yes, it's like mine is saying... They disagree with my being here, but they're not being (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Because they don't know anything about us anyway. A woman: No. They just, they just kind of
A woman: accept them some information, but they don't, they don't wanna look at it. They just (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, let's see what the rest of the Sura says, verse 10. In Case of War
[60:10] O you who believe, when believing women (abandon the enemy and) ask for asylum with you, you shall test them. GOD is fully aware of their belief. Once you establish that they are believers, you shall not return them to the disbelievers.
[60:10] ...They are not lawful to remain married to them, nor shall the disbelievers be allowed to marry them. Give back the dowries that the disbelievers have paid. You commit no error by marrying them, so long as you pay them their due dowries.
[60:10] ...Do not keep disbelieving wives (if they wish to join the enemy). You may ask them for the dowry you had paid, and they may ask for what they paid. This is GOD's rule; He rules among you. GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
This probably will not, will never apply to us, but what this is saying is when two camps are fighting,
one camp are disbelievers, another camp is believers, and some, some women on the disbelievers' side join the believers,
you do not have to obtain an, an official divorce for the women.
You can consider them divorced without, without any official action.
And the same if women from the believers' side decide to disbelieve and join the disbelievers' camp,
God is actually telling the believers to give them back their dowries and divorce them.
If this is what they want.
Number 11,
[60:11] If any of your wives join the enemies' ...
Oh, I was a little ahead of myself.
[60:11] If any of your wives join the enemies' camp, and you are forced to fight, you shall force the enemy to compensate the men who lost their wives, by giving them what they spent on their wives. You shall reverence GOD, in whom you believe.
Number 12,
[60:12] O you prophet, when the believing women (who abandoned the disbelievers) to seek asylum with you pledge to you that they will not set up any idols besides GOD, nor steal, nor commit adultery, nor kill their children, nor fabricate any falsehood, nor disobey your righteous orders, you shall accept their pledge, and pray to GOD to forgive them. GOD is Forgiver, Most Merciful.
Now, when number 12 says "O you prophet", what does this tell us?
Dr. Khalifa: Because this is at the time of the prophet Muhammad. It is not applicable to us. A man: (unintelligible). Yes.
Starting at verse 10.
Number 13,
[60:13] O you who believe, do not befriend people with whom GOD is angry, ...
This repeats verse 1 and verse 9.
[60:13] O you who believe, do not befriend people with whom GOD is angry, and who are hopelessly stuck in disbelief; ...
It's very important, "hopelessly stuck in disbelief."
You have to use your own judgement if the person, if there is hope that the person may become a believer or not.
And if there is hope that the person may become a believer, you better be as diplomatic as you can to help them.
You have, you have a lot at stake, by the way, when you do that.
Because when you help somebody come to the truth, you get a lot of credit.
So, God gives us incentives, lots of positive incentives to do that.
So, if you sense that the person is, there is hope that the person may become a believer,
Dr. Khalifa: you should be as diplomatic as can be, and you use your own judgement in that.
A woman: This, so, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But there is no war. Yeah. This is in case of war.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes I know.
Dr. Khalifa: They do all kinds of strange things.
A man: Al-Salaamu ‘Alaykum
Dr. Khalifa: Hey!
Parivash: Wow! Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: You made it!
A woman: Wow.
Dr. Khalifa: Come on in, come on in.
A woman: Alhamdu Lillah
A woman: Salam.
Parivash: Salam Dr. Khalifa: Salam. Come on, here, here, come here.
A man: Oh, excellent!
A man: Hi!
People: Salam.
A woman: Alhamdu Lillah
A man: Sorry, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it's fine.
A man: The door was locked but (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: "With whom God is angry", these are your criteria.
[60:13] ... and who are hopelessly stuck in disbelief; ...
[60:13] ... hopelessly stuck in disbelief; they are just as hopeless as the disbelievers who are already in the graves.
In other words, there's absolutely no hope for them, therefore you cannot, you cannot defend them.
Dr. Khalifa: This is why you have to use your own judgement.
A man: Patience.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, give up.
Dr. Khalifa: There he is, he's here.
Dr. Khalifa: This is Mardana. Mardana: Very glad to be here.
Dr. Khalifa: The Canadian group were asking about you.
Behrouz: Yes. I hug everybody later.
Behrouz: Hi, how are you?
A woman: You promise?
Behrouz: Yes, yes. If you accept our dirty clothes and...
A woman: Yes.
Behrouz: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Let us finish the page, page 551.
The Sura 61, "The Column (Al-Suff)"
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
[61:1] Glorifying GOD is everything in the heavens and everything on earth. ...
Think about that.
Can we, can we keep the kids quiet somehow?
Tell them to lower their voices.
[61:1] Glorifying GOD is everything in the heavens and everything on earth. ...
The carpet, walls, glorifying God.
I think we went into details of this before.
It was a kind of surprise.
This carpet is made of certain atoms.
And every atom has certain number of electrons.
And electrons are rotating in specific orbits.
And this is God's law. So, they are glorifying God.
In Sura 17, God says,
(17:44) وَإِن مِّن شَىْءٍ إِلَّا يُسَبِّحُ بِحَمْدِهِۦ
There is nothing that does not glorify God.
Even the disbelievers.
Dr. Khalifa: And the rest of the verse here says "we do not understand their glorification."
A man: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the disbelievers' bodies, disbelievers cannot control the heartbeats, or the lungs breathing.
Feroz: Only difference is they're doing it unwillingly.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: Rashad, God gives an interesting example of shadow. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: God says, (unintelligible)
Edip: They think that disobey God, but their shadow obeys God's rule and so (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. I was just writing a footnote about this yesterday.
And I said that the solar clocks bear witness to that.
There's, there is a solar clock here in the university in front of the observatory.
And it's very accurate because it's based on the shadow.
It tells you exactly what time it is.
It's an eternal clock.
So,
[61:1] Glorifying GOD is everything in the heavens and everything on earth. He is the Almighty, Most Wise.
[61:2] O you who believe, why do you say what you do not do?
[61:3] Most abominable in the sight of GOD is that you say what you do not do.
So, if you're asking somebody to do the five Prayers, you better be doing them yourself.
Number four,
[61:4] GOD loves those who fight in His cause to be united in one column, like the bricks in one wall.
There is no, there shouldn't be any, any differences.
We have to be one.
This is why we see in Sura 6 that God condemns sectarianism.
God says, says "those who divide the religion into sects do not belong to God or the prophet."
And they, they hear this practically every day. But they still say "I'm a Shafe'i, I'm a Malki, I'm a Hanbali, I'm a Sunni, I'm a Shia, Ahmadi."
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Barbara, what are you?
Barbara: A submitter, Rashad. Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't think we have any trouble under this roof saying who we are.
A woman: A lot of people (unintelligible). A lot of them, they just say "Well, this is not (unintelligible)"
Dr. Khalifa: It's the only thing they know.
Dr. Khalifa: But you go to any typical masjid in any Muslim country, and under the same roof you're gonna find different sects.
Edip: Oh, today, Rashad, that Arab came.
Dr. Khalifa: Is he an Arab?
Edip: Yes, he was Yemeni.
Dr. Khalifa: Uh-uh.
Edip: And he came before, he said, he came, he said, "now this masjid, that masjid, there are a lot of hatred and bad things."
"I hate that, I don't like, I want to make search, research."
Edip: And he came here, only for this reason, they have trouble there.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, they always do. They have fistfights.
This is in every masjid.
I know.
So, this Sura is entitled "Al-Suff (The Column)."
Like the bricks in one wall.
[61:5] Recall that Moses said to his people, "O my people, why do you hurt me, even though you know that I am GOD's messenger to you?" When they deviated, GOD diverted their hearts. For GOD does not guide the wicked people.
So, that's it.
And then, we open to general discussions.
Dr. Khalifa: Any questions, Azar?
Azar: No.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't believe it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yesterday, I asked "do you have any questions?" She said "how are you?"
Parivash: (6:159) إِنَّ ٱلَّذِينَ فَرَّقُوا۟ دِينَهُمْ وَكَانُوا۟ شِيَعًۭا
Parivash: 6:1.. Dr. Khalifa: 6:159
Parivash: 159
A woman: Dr. Khalifa, I have a question.
A woman: Is there any specific rule that men always have to prepare for the (unintelligible)? Just the (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is the way that came to us all the way from Abraham.
And usually, if God wants to set a precedent for the subsequent generations,
God would create a situation or circumstances that will force this issue and then we'll have a precedent that a woman is leading the Prayer.
But that never happened, and the innovations are a very serious matter.
Dr. Khalifa: So, just so, not start any innovation, we're keeping this, this rule.
A woman: But I think in my own house, does my father always have to prepare (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: I would say "yes", because of this same reason.
This has been always the rule, and any change in it would be an innovation.
So, it's not worth it. It's not worth it.
But from the logical point of view, a woman leading the Prayer is not, is not... the woman is dignified, and it'll be more distracting for the men.
It's very dangerous to start a new innovation, something new.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: There's, there are 2 places that...
Dr. Khalifa: That's a bad question.
A man: We're talking about... Dr. Khalifa: No, no, go ahead.
A man: We're talking about cuts in Quran.
A man: One is when they're cutting the thief's hand. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: The other one when Joseph, those ladies cut their hands because of...
A man: And there's a third one that Pharaoh tells those people who follow Moses, says "I will cut your hands and feet on alternate sides."
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: Oh, I don't know, but I mean, my question is, is the third one similar to the first or the second? Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: So I... Dr. Khalifa: It's neither.
A man: Pardon?
Dr. Khalifa: The word used for Joseph and the women, and 19 verses later in Sura Joseph, and also cutting the hand of the thief, that's the same word.
A man: The same word.
Dr. Khalifa: But the word used for the people who commit gross crimes and fight God, and the word that Pharaoh is using is different.
It's Qatte'a (قَطِّعَ) and Qatta'a (قَطَّعَ)
Dr. Khalifa: You see the difference?
A man: Well, I don't know. I don't understand.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, listen, listen, just listen to the word. Qatta'a (قَطَّعَ), this is the root for the hand of the thief.
Dr. Khalifa: But for the people who commit gross crimes, it's Qatte'a (قَطِّعَ).
A man: So, the thief and Joseph, basically exactly the same. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Same word, exactly.
A man: What's the fourth one?
Edip: It is, Rashad said. Dr. Khalifa: Qatte'a (قَطِّعَ).
Edip: The people that fight against believers, they could be killed and also...
A man: No, that's the same one that Pharaoh used. Edip: Yes, that is...
Dr. Khalifa: They commit heinous crimes.
Dr. Khalifa: Stealing is a very specific crime.
Edip: Yes, the difference is very important because this root, Qatte'a (قَطِّعَ), is strongly punishment. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: (unintelligible), It is to make it stronger. Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Edip: The other is Qatta'a (قَطَّعَ).
Dr. Khalifa: God gave us mathematical evidence, so...
A woman: Rashad. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Earlier this afternoon when we were studying, a question came up about Jumu‘ah, Jumu'ah Prayer.
A woman: If you came in and the first, part of the first Khutba was given already, how many Rak'ats do you have to make?
Dr. Khalifa: Two.
A woman: Ok.
Edip: You missed... A woman: Could you talk about, elaborate a little bit because it wasn't a very forward answer?
Dr. Khalifa: This is a straightforward answer.
Dr. Khalifa:If you miss the whole Khutba and come, the people haven't done the two Rak'ats, you do only two Rak'ats. Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because you went to the place and chances are you're gonna ask the people what was the subject, what did they talk about.
It will, it will be discussed.
Dr. Khalifa: Also, you're Praying in a congregation. So, the credit carries over, in other words.
A woman: Ok. Thank you.
A woman: If you're alone on Friday... Dr. Khalifa: You cannot Pray. A woman: Then, you do 4?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, even though you missed the whole thing...
Dr. Khalifa: You give yourself a Khutba, you'll be accused of being schizo.
So, the word Jumu'ah by definition is group.
Yes, go ahead. You have a guest for one night, Azhar and Shahrukh.
Dr. Khalifa: Because you came too early.
A man: She's over there. A man: She just...
A man: She's over there. Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead. A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, she... A man: She's...
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No, she wasn't.
Dr. Khalifa: There she is.
A man: (unintelligible) A man: Mã Shã Allãh.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, go ahead. Do you need people to help you move in?
A man: No, no, tomorrow.
Dr. Khalifa: We have great muscles, see? Sheikh Mahmoud's muscles, and (unintelligible) and Edip's.
A man: In fact, tomorrow IN SHAA ALLAH, we have to (unintelligible).
A man: Or you have a truck. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: A truck.
Dr. Khalifa: Just say when. Tomorrow morning?
A man: Yes. We have to... Dr. Khalifa: Tonight?
A man: No, not tonight because they're closed. We have to take (unintelligible).
A man: I'm pulling my car with it.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. A man: And then bring his car back.
Dr. Khalifa: Just say when and we'll be here, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: He's gone. Dr. Khalifa: No, he's gone.
A man: Thank you.
A woman: .... this life because...
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Edip: May I say something?
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Edip: This is a good point. But if you think further, God is capable to create a system that even if everybody live well
Edip: and also can they survive. God is, it's God's system now we're talking about, but God can create another, create another system that even everybody could survive on the earth.
Dr. Khalifa: But we're talking about the system we have now. Edip: Ok.
Edip: But it is possible for God.
But why God decided on the system.
I have also additionally another answer.
The final is the most, the important thing, the test, the (unintelligible) test, worship God alone.
Everything, for example, to be poor or to be rich.
You just see many rich people, they do not see the message because they are rich, they are proud, they don't involve, they don't take care.
But many poor people, they accept.
Sometimes differently in this test, all poor to be poor or to be rich has the same disadvantage and advantage.
And if you look at the perspective of the test and the final result, they all have the same,
Edip: I'd say different but equal problems and equal advantages.
Dr. Khalifa: What is, what is happening to communism today?
Communism failed.
Where Karl Marx said "everybody has... all people have to be equal."
It didn't work.
Nasser destroyed Egypt using this principle.
Because all of a sudden the boss will call somebody to do something.
"No, I'm not gonna do it. I'm just as... I'm just like you."
Dr. Khalifa: And the whole country stopped from that moment.
A man: Rashad, I think if the system was like, like Edip said, everything was equal and so on and
A man: God would make it work also the other way, then we would have some (unintelligible) not just this world. (unintelligible)
A man: He's right. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: It's not exactly if it was a condition. We accepted to come over here. For example, I asked God to send me over here.
"I'm going to have this much problem over there."
"(unintelligible) everything, but still I would glorify you."
Somebody asked me "ok, if you make Me, send me over there, let me kill, still I'm glorifying You or purify."
A man: This is the only condition we accepted before we came to this world.
Dr. Khalifa: Say it again.
A man: Before we came to here, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: we accept all of things that is going to happen for us.
A man: In this world? A man: Yeah, send us all to this world
A man: for everything bad or good is going to happen for us, still we are going to glorify you.
A man: (unintelligible) some of us (unintelligible)
A man: We accepted that (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: We accepted the freedom of choice.
Dr. Khalifa: We didn't, we didn't... if you, if you...
A man: For example, one day you said, for example, the horse comes to this world and is...
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I see. Those, those submitted, yeah they submitted to God, the horse, the dog, the stars, the trees. A man: (unintelligible) for example, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily. They just, they just accepted to submit and come to this world and perform certain functions in total submission.
Dr. Khalifa: But we, we didn't know what we were in for.
A man: (unintelligible) Sorry.
Dr. Khalifa: It's Ok.
Materials of This World: All That The Disbelievers Get
[43:33] If it were not that all the people might become one (disbelieving) congregation, we would have granted everyone who disbelieves in the Most Gracious mansions with silver roofs, and stairs upon which they could climb.
So, because this is all they get in this world, God saying, you know, their destiny is so awful
in the Hereafter that God wishes to give each one of them a few million dollars and a mansion and let them have fun here for 60 or 70 years.
Because after that they're heading for Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: But then, the test would become more difficult for the believers.
A woman: Rashad, I have a questions.
We read in the Quran that the rich believer is better than poor, but throughout the Quran also we read that
A woman: material (unintelligible) is, you know, in Hereafter, but how come God is telling us that rich believer is better than the poor?
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Let us say we were all poor, we're all believers.
We are all believers and we barely, barely make, we're very poor, how will you print this Quran for example?
Dr. Khalifa: It's a good thing that we have this here and we sent it to (unintelligible) coming all the way from Nigeria because he received the message and the Quran and
Dr. Khalifa: books. A woman: We cannot (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It doesn't make any difference. Your dollars are already assigned to you but go ahead and ask.
The reason, the reason "go ahead and ask and God says so" is because it's a form of worship when you ask God but it does not make any difference.
Your dollars from birth to death are already assigned.
Dr. Khalifa: Ask Jan about that.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, (unintelligible) A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But you know, as it is with the believers, you're guaranteed all your needs, your health, your wealth, guaranteed a perfect life for a believer.
And you may have zero in the bank but you will not worry and you have peace of mind and the IRS cannot touch you.
Dr. Khalifa: You have your money deposited up there.
Edip: Rashad, the fact of that rich believers is better than poor believers, something is open up to abuse, for abuse. I think the...
Dr. Khalifa: Anything is open to abuse.
Edip: I think the...
Dr. Khalifa: Anything is open to abuse. Anything. Believe me.
Edip: Something that is too open for abuse and people try, and they could treat each other according to their money and it becomes, how do you say it, like a company.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Edip: Hoarding more money as if (unintelligible) I don't know that probably (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: That's what God said.
Remember that the common denominator is believer.
Dr. Khalifa: The Rich Believer is Better than the Poor Believer
Edip: There is encouraging. I think it could be told in different ways.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Edip: For example, believers try to be rich, must try to be rich and work hard. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Edip: Don't be lazy.
Dr. Khalifa: You're not trying to be rich? Edip: This is the... Excuse me?
Dr. Khalifa: You're not... listen, listen Apamea. Apamea. Listen. A woman: Apamea is Apamea.
Dr. Khalifa: You're not trying to be rich?
Edip: Who? Dr. Khalifa: You.
Edip: How do you know?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm asking.
Dr. Khalifa: He's criticizing trying to be rich.
Ok. Now, you're not trying to be rich?
Do you want to be rich?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm not excusing you.
Parivash: But Rashad, but I think he thinks this is a good point. He said "this is good."
Dr. Khalifa: No, no. He's saying this is not a good point.
Parivash: No, I think he said...
Dr. Khalifa: Trying to be rich. Is that good or bad?
Edip: Depends on your (unintelligible).
Edip: If we have other things to do first of all, you should choose this and later... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Let's take you for example. Do you want to be, do you want to be rich?
Edip: Sure, I want to be rich. Dr. Khalifa: Why?
Edip: Why not?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm glad you're watching, Apamea.
Edip: Sure, it's a good thing.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Edip: But it is not just so... Dr. Khalifa: Alright, we agree.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God said
Edip: Yeah, for believers to be rich is surely is better than to be poor but...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Thank you very much.
Edip: What you mean by... there are sometimes expression of (unintelligible), if sometimes the... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't wanna say "the rich believer is better than the poor believer"?
A woman: This is something funny.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, (a man)
A man: I think, yes, a rich, a rich believer is better than the poor believer,
in the sense that for the rich believer to appreciate the gifts that are given to him,
A man: that it's from God and then use these gifts in the cause of God Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: to charity, building mosques in the cause of God and
A man: do his other obligations and Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: and knowing very well that all these things are not his own making
A man: not his own education, intelligence, wisdom Dr. Khalifa: Charity.
A man: but they are from the Almighty Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm telling you it's not easy to be a rich believer. More difficult, did you know that?
Dr. Khalifa: It is more difficult. It is more responsibility. And I'll give you the example of Solomon.
Ok. Solomon was very rich.
Dr. Khalifa: He was the richest human alive and, and he became distracted with his horses. What did he do?
A man: Yes. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He got rid of his horses. Yes.
Edip: But by this way... Dr. Khalifa: So, that's, it's very difficult because you get distracted.
Edip: By (unintelligible) this, we're saying Solomon is better than Job because he was a rich believer if we took this, add the criteria according to Quran, maybe richest man (unintelligible).
A woman: But I don't think...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the rich believer is, listen, there's nothing to know about the rich believer being better than the poor believer because God said so.
So, we can only debate on the, on some details but the principle, God already said the principle,
the rich believer is better than the poor believer Sura 16.
Dr. Khalifa: We cannot fool around with the principle but you can discuss...
A man: Is it be the rich (unintelligible) more difficult? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: To get into, become, you have to believe (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Because they don't need God.
This is why I'm using you as an example.
Is it better for you to be poor or rich, you, as a believer?
You're the same believer. Your belief in God is certain, IN SHAA ALLAH, it will never change.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, is it better for you to be poor or rich?
Edip: Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: For all concerns, answer, no, answer, answer, answer my question first and then...
Edip: Let me first...
Dr. Khalifa: Is it better to be, for you, to be poor or rich, in your opinion? Is it better to be rich or poor?
Edip: Sure.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure what?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Let me, let me, one point, Rashad, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: The word "believer" is not something... it is very related subject. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: For example, there are maybe two believers, both of them believers but one of them is more appreciated but
Edip: God didn't give, God says "I give you, I will (unintelligible)."
Edip: If God... Dr. Khalifa: No, no, we're talking about equal believers. They're both believers.
Edip: Rashad, God says... Dr. Khalifa: You've reached, you've reached the top as far as belief is concerned.
Edip: (49:13) إِنَّ أَكْرَمَكُمْ عِندَ ٱللَّهِ أَتْقَىٰكُمْ God says.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Both of them are in the same Taqwa (تقوا), same belief, same degree of Taqwa (تقوا).
Dr. Khalifa: Now, which one is... Edip: But we cannot say this.
Dr. Khalifa: Why not? This is what God is saying. We're talking about two equal... Go ahead. You have some very good arguments.
A man: Let's say, there are two people. Ok. Both spend same amount of time, time for this class, thinking about God,
for example, read the Quran and whatever that they think is being righteous. To me, I think their work
I say they both have even the same knowledge. (unintelligible) I say "Ok, I need 8 hours of sleep."
And I do whatever I do and I only want for example 8 hours. The other one says
A man: "ok, I sleep only 6 hours. I work harder." And that's the reason that he became richer and he has more money. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Then, to me that person works harder.
And we can say "yes, their belief are the same." They are both righteous. Their belief are the same.
A man: Yes, that one is better because he works harder and achieves whatever he got, what he has.
Dr. Khalifa: No, even without working harder, say, I want to... Because I've see people
who don't work at all and they are very rich anyway.
Yes, but if they are, they are both believers,
then the rich, I mean, according to the Quran, what God is telling us is that the rich has a better chance to be charitable, to help the others, to
Dr. Khalifa: to publish the Quran or whatever. The things that need money. The thing that is what...
A man: And the poor believer (unintelligible) one is poor and if you're a really a believer imagine coming home
and they should come home, you couldn't know, you will know that there is no food in the house and time to (unintelligible) just
coming home around the sunset Prayers and, you know, four or five kids in the house with the wife
and he went out to work, coming home, he couldn't get anything and when he comes into the household
the kids crying all over the places and the wife making faces,
A man: you can (unintelligible) Prayer at that time. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Distractions. A man: A rich man, you don't have any of these problems.
A man: And the moment you come home, you know the food is there, the kids are playing with their motorbikes and all these things. He goes Praying and then (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: You concentrate on the Prayer. A man: You can concentrate on the Prayer. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly. That also.
Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, we cannot fool around with the principle that the rich believer is better than the poor believer.
And, ok, Edip wants to make a lot of money so he can publish a translation in Turkey and
Dr. Khalifa: build a mosque in his hometown and buy a few dresses for Apamea. Apamea: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: And he's gonna be a millionaire IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: Is it possible that a believer be rich?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? No? Why? A man: I don't think so.
Dr. Khalifa: Solomon was a believer.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: He was very, very, very, very rich.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? A man: (unintelligible)
A man: A believer could be rich. Because (unintelligible) believer.
A man: I don't think we're ever gonna be rich.
Dr. Khalifa: Why?
A man: Because you are going to by the Honorable. You know you are going to visit the God, see the God, (unintelligible)
A man: So, I think you are going to spend all of your money in the right way. Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, not necessarily A man: (unintelligible) you will be a rich...
Dr. Khalifa: But he'll be a rich (unintelligible). If he's spending all his money, he is rich.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Also, we don't know how much money is written for us. A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we have to work as hard as possible. It's God's perfect system.
A man: Only God knows how much He has assigned to you. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, we don't know.
So, we have to knock on all the doors and one of them, some of them, the right ones will open.
Dr. Khalifa: But you have to knock.
Edip: So, why you cannot be PhDs.
Edip: It's Farhad. Farhad is going (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You never know.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Somebody push the door. It is getting cold.
A woman: Rashad, is poor, isn't poor and rich relative to, to the place that the poor and rich people live? It is said just now about Solomon and Job. Job was rich within where Job was. What richness meant in Job...
Dr. Khalifa: So, Job was rich. Period.
A man: (unintelligible) A woman: very wealthy? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: For Job, so, ...
Dr. Khalifa: No. Period. He was very wealthy. Period.
Dr. Khalifa: He became poor for a while. A woman: Right and then he...
Dr. Khalifa: Then, he was, became twice as rich. A woman: Twice as rich. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Right. So, even, so, even though he wasn't as wealthy as Solomon, he was a wealthy person in that time. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: So, poor and rich have to be relative to where poor and rich really is because in some places
rich may mean a million dollars and that's really wealthy. It can do just as much as 10 million dollars
A woman: may be able to do in another place. So, poor and rich is relative to the place. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible). I think the statement of a poor... a rich believer is better than a poor is a very good
character building statement for a believer. It gives you the need to strive, it makes you want to
A woman: to build yourself to do something. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And it makes you want to give. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Definitely.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, I think we'll stop here. We usually read two pages every morning and then we're, we're open to discussion.
A man: Rashad Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: When God says "a rich believer is better than a poor." It means in this world, right? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Not Hereafter. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Also, in the Hereafter. There will be ranks in the Hereafter. I think
this is where Heaven and Hell... we can think of it, if we apply the terms of this world,
a ditch digger out, when it is 110 degrees here in Tucson and somebody is digging ditches out there,
he's hoping that he will save enough money someday to import cheese from Greece and sell it here. You know, stop...
In other words, there is a hope that this will end, the ditch digging. But if, in the Hereafter a ditch digger is a ditch digger forever,
there's no hope. This is why it is Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there are ranks over there and when the people in Hell are assigned those low ranks, they know that this is forever. There's no promotion
A man: God is also saying that those (unintelligible) are the most righteous. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: I think...
Dr. Khalifa: Over there, in the Hereafter? A man: (unintelligible) were rich.
Dr. Khalifa: There will, there'll be ranks. In fact, we have three general ranks. We have the High Heaven, we have the Low Heaven.
And then, we have Hell. So, God gives us descriptions of the High Heaven and the Low Heaven.
In the High Heaven, the water flows. In the Low Heaven, you have to pump, you have to work for it, right?
So, that's the difference, yeah, Sura 55, God describes the High Heaven and the Low Heaven.
And God says in the High Heaven, the water flows like a spring. It's right there, ready.
But in the Lower Heaven, you have to pump. It's all, of course, allegory, relative.
You have to work for the... God tells us in the High Heaven, there is all kinds of fruit.
In the Lower Heaven, there is a limited number of fruit. God names names, certain fruits.
But in the High Heaven, God says there's all kinds of fruit.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there are, there are ranks and limitations even there.
A man: I (unintelligible) the ranks, but God doesn't, God does say that closest to Me is the most righteous. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: So, I don't see any mention about the God. That's, that's my question.
Dr. Khalifa: The closest to God will be in the High Heaven.
A man: No, I, I think there are...
Dr. Khalifa: You're talking about the Hereafter? A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the closest to God will be in the High Heaven.
Edip: Yeah, righteous, more righteous.
A man: More righteous, not, not the, not the most righteous and wealthy.
A man: I think, let me...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but this, this implies being in the High Heaven means wealthier, richer. A man: Yes.
Audience: I think (unintelligible)
A man: Richness of this world differs from the richness of the other world. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, you're saying that a rich believer here can be in a lower rank than a poor believer here, over there?
A man: Yes, I think that's...
Dr. Khalifa: You're, that's right. You're right. It's not necessarily the same.
You take two believers, one is rich and one is poor here. This may be reversed over there but in any case... Yeah, I think I understand your question now.
But in any case, it is fantastic triumph to be in the Lower Heaven or the High Heaven over there. Yes. And there is no jealousy.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, there is no jealousy and there is no... everyone is perfectly happy. The jealousy will be erased from the dictionary in the Heaven in the High Heaven or the Low Heaven.
A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: What do you mean?
Dr. Khalifa: The feelings of ecstasy and joy and happiness, yes.
A man: Rashad Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: My 11-year-old son was asking me "why do you have to eat in Heaven? Do you age?" Do you change for example, if I die at age 14...
Dr. Khalifa: You don't eat in Heaven.
A man: So, why there are fruits, why God is telling you there are...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it's all allegory. There are no fruits.
A woman: Just imagine, Rashad, if you...
Dr. Khalifa: There are no trees and no fruits unless you want to. You can make them if you want to. Just look at them and reminisce about the first life.
A man: Rivers of milk and honey. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And honey and wine.
A man: ...or it's just all allegory?
Dr. Khalifa: It's all allegory.
A man: Because we don't know what's it really, we don't know...
Edip: It doesn't mean like it's here that it displays. It doesn't (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: We can describe this. (unintelligible)
Edip: For example, Hell, the allegory of Hell is very... fire and in the middle of it, there is a tree.
Edip: And if you accept tree here that, that we know and fire that we know
Edip: the tree and the fire, it's completely separate, it's all allegory.
Parivash: Yeah, but in the Quran that said "in the Hereafter, when they see the some kind of fruit, they remember and say 'this is exactly what God gave us at the first time.'"
Parivash: The first time is not this life. The first time they remember exactly in the Heaven, yeah?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's, God says in the same verse that we thus give them allegorical descriptions.
Parivash: Yeah, ok, but...
Dr. Khalifa: (2:25) وَأُتُوا۟ بِهِۦ مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا
Parivash: Ok. In that, I'm talking... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Oh, no, no. He said (2:25) وَأُتُوا۟ بِهِۦ مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا
Parivash: Yes.
Edip: She, her understanding is a lot different.
Dr. Khalifa: The same. Yes, I know.
Edip: different.
Dr. Khalifa: We used to understand it this way.
Edip: Yes, we used to understand it... Parivash, (2:25) وَأُتُوا۟ بِهِۦ مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: means allegorical. Edip: we have been given a similar, a similar (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: This is an amazing play of words look at this word
Edip: God says "they have been given an allegory of Paradise." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: It's the expression (unintelligible) A woman: Oh, Wow! Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Listen to, look at this word Mutashabehan (مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا),
Dr. Khalifa: and the way God used it. It's amazing. Ok. Mutashabehan (مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا) means "similar." Mutashabehan (مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا) also means "allegorical."
Dr. Khalifa: So, if people want, if people want to believe that it means "we get apples like the apples here and bananas like the bananas here", fine, they will understand it that way.
Edip: Rashad, these... Parivash: No, because, no when I saw (unintelligible)
Edip: By this said (unintelligible). Mutashabehan (مُتَشَـٰبِهًۭا), the verse. Dr. Khalifa: An allegory. Yes. Parivash: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I said if the people like in the past.
Parviash: No, but Rashad, I mean, when I read it, I thought
Parivash: this is the allegory of the fruit, for example, but not the same as this here, the life, the first Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Parivash: we remember in the Day of Resurrection, the Heaven, everything, and we remember there, not here.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, oh, ok.
Parivash: And they say "oh,..." Dr. Khalifa: Ok. She's ahead of us. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, she's, she's ahead of both of us.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh. Dr. Khalifa: Wonderful.
Dr. Khalifa: Her babies are supposed to be asleep at this time.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, look at John. He's not awake yet.
A man: Makan. Dr. Khalifa: Huh? A man: Makan.
A man: Rasahd, Rashad...
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
Parivash: When you are teaching, starting to teach and after, you said "ok..."
Parivash: Anybody have, anybody have this question, and I think maybe when, when you teach us and, because I was the one that I interrupted that I said something.
Parivash: But it's not better to just listen and you teach and after finishing...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, because this brings up lots of points.
A man: Sometimes... Parivash: Because you forget...
Dr. Khalifa: No. Edip: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Edip: (unintelligible) is more.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, no, the water is the vast vast majority.
Dr. Khalifa: We're talking about the solid mass of the planet earth. If we take the solid mass and compress it, the water will be 9 times as many, at 90%.
Edip: Early, my suggestion was this, that the living creatures (unintelligible) because God made earth with living creatures.
A man: Hydrogen (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But no, there is (unintelligible) even, even the Earth.
Edip: Also, Rashad, for example, stars Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Stars, also creature of God. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: For example, there is no water in the sun.
Edip: I think...
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, there is. You know what the sun is made of?
Edip: Hydrogen
Dr. Khalifa: Hydrogen. And what's the water made of?
Edip: Hydrogen and Oxygen. A woman: And Oxygen.
Dr. Khalifa: There is no, no, no way around it. Hydrogen and Oxygen. It's H2O.
Dr. Khalifa: Edip has the flies. He has a pocket full of flies, put in the oatmeal.
Edip: What is this?
Dr. Khalifa: We'll never tell you. Just don't change. Stay as you are.
A woman: Someday you might say (unintelligible)
A woman: We don't wanna miss anything. You can say it. I said we hit the jackpot.
Dr. Khalifa: God created every, every... He has a good point. Actually, Edip has a very good point.
Because God talks about the creatures that walk on their bellies like snakes,
or two or four. So, God is talking about living creatures. It's a very good point that Edip is raising.
Dr. Khalifa: But I'd like to give him rough time, see how far I can push him. Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Because what, what makes this... he's talking about the stars and the sun, also, but what makes this restricted to
living creatures like he said is that God says "some walk on two legs and some walk on their bellies."
Now, living organisms are, are 85 to 99% water. We're talking about plants, animals and humans.
46,
And life cannot sustain without water in those creatures, all of them one.
This is the one common, one thing that's common to all living creatures is water.
[24:46] We have sent down to you clarifying revelations, then GOD guides whoever wills in a straight path.
God Sends Instructions Through His Messenger
[24:47] They say, "We believe in GOD and in the messenger, and we obey," but then some of them turn away. They are not believers.
[24:48] When they are invited to GOD and His messenger to judge among them, some of them get upset.
Parivash knows that. Quite a few of them.
[24:49] However, if the judgment is in their favor, they readily accept it!
[24:50] Is there a disease in their hearts? Are they doubtful? Are they afraid that GOD and His messenger may treat them unfairly? In fact, it is they who are unfair.
Believers Unhesitatingly Obey God and His Messenger
[24:51] The only utterance of the believers, whenever invited to GOD and His messenger to judge in their affairs, is to say, "We hear and we obey." These are the winners.
[24:52] Those who obey GOD and His messenger, and reverence GOD and observe Him, these are the triumphant ones.
[24:53] They swear by GOD, solemnly, that if you commanded them to mobilize, they would mobilize. Say, "Do not swear. Obedience is an obligation. GOD is fully Cognizant of everything you do."
My own experiences with this is, for example, the issue of 40 years when it surfaced,
there was so much opposition to it, mainly because we are mean creatures, you know.
"Why does God put them in Heaven? Put them all in Hell." This is what they were telling me.
And they argued and we had to use a lot of discussion back and forth, we wasted a lot of time and effort.
So, had they say "we hear and we obey" and then, take off from that point, we would have saved a lot of time and effort.
It would have saved themselves a lot of time.
So, this is why God said,
[24:51] The only utterance of the believers, whenever invited to GOD and His messenger to judge in their affairs, is to say, "We hear and we obey." These are the winners.
Because they saved their time and effort.
There were quite a few people, you know, this issue dragged with them for almost a year.
And the funny thing is some of them I thought they accepted it.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, a year later, I found that they didn't, they're still having trouble with it.
A man: In fact, that would be that we should have questions, accept it...
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, I did say. Now, they should question it, but after accepting it. In other words, God says so "ok, we accept it."
Now, let us see, why, why is God setting the age of 40 and why isn't it 45 or 30?
We can discuss that but after accepting it and knowing it. But what I found was they actually could not accept it.
It didn't make sense to them.
And I told them "ok, well, give me the break, the line. Where is the line, the cut off line of responsibility? Is it 6 years? When somebody dies at the age 7, does he go to... is he responsible?
"or at the age of 17? 21? What is it? I mean, give me... ." There is no age in the Quran except 40,
for the age of responsibility. In other words, they were just objecting without, without having an alternative.
A man: Rashad, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: The new age is when we start praying and we're obligated to fast (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: In here.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's about one week.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
A man: What about me?
Dr. Khalifa: Explain it, Ihsan.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You explain it. Right. Parivash: Yes. Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Explain it for Erik, for me.
Ihsan: Well, you have to raise your hands. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ihsan: Both hands must (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Did you see how he prayed?
Dr. Khalifa: No, but he started, I assure you he started before one week.
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, our babies start before they are born. A woman: Yes.
A woman: As soon as (unintelligible) from the, from the hospital, (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Before he (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) stand up, before stand up, as soon as he can stand up, he can (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Well, listen. Edip's, Edip's baby is not even one week yet, and he or she is listening to the Quran. Did you know that?
A man: Oh, I understand. Society, society that is obligated. You don't do this, but it will be 40. So, if you don't Pray until 40, you have to (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, but you see, Hany will gain from this, what he's doing, from his Prayer.
Dr. Khalifa: Cause this is, this is my personal experience, for example. I started like Hany and I never quit and I think I'm benefitting from this.
A woman: My father (unintelligible) Edip: Rashad, I think...
Edip: The question that Azar asking is Mehdi. Dr. Khalifa: Mehdi.
Edip: Mehdi is asking "if you say the point, early you said, responsibility age is 40 which you cannot ask people that are younger than 40, you pray (unintelligible). We have..."
Dr. Khalifa: How do we make a decision?
A man: (unintelligible) A woman: How do you know?
Edip: Let...
Edip: The point, Rashad, that we misunderstand, age 40 is the maximum age, the maximum limit which if you, for example, if I
Edip: now, I am before 40, I heard the message, I know it's true. If I try to abuse it, God knows, God knows my innermost thoughts and God will mislead me and I may lose my chance to be a believer after 40.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, there is more to it than that. There's more to it than this also.
Dr. Khalifa: Although it will not happen, but theoretically, a person is a strong believer at the age of 20 and he practices and then he dies at the age of 35,
Dr. Khalifa: he may go to the High Heaven instead of the Low Heaven. There's a big difference there.
Edip: Because we have a chance of (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is a big earth.
A man: That is true.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, but to answer Mehdi's question more, in more detail, we're required to make the decision before the age of 40.
Dr. Khalifa: So, how are we going to make a decision if we don't know how the Prayers and the fasting and actually practices.
A man: Rashad,... A woman: Rashad, time to investigate. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: If we miss a Prayer, we feel bad (unintelligible), but if anyone under 40, I mean, there is not that much pressure on them.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure
A man: Sometimes, we're too lazy to get up for it.
Dr. Khalifa: You're assuming that the person knows that he or she will die before 40.
A man: But it isn't, technically, I'm asking because in Iran and some other countries they put such, they put such limited age like, like girls, I guess, they start praying at 9 and then
A man: boys at 14 or 15 something like, yeah, they have this...
Dr. Khalifa: I see. Well, this is different, though.
A man: They have no basis in the, basis.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, well, in the Sunni world, the age is 5 and you beat them at 7. This is their Hadith.
A man: Beat them at 7?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It says "teach your kids to pray at the age of 5 and beat them up at the age of 7 for, to pray."
Who's left?
Are you sniffering?
It's true.
You see, ...مروا أبناء You know this Hadith, right?
مروا أبناءكم بالصلاة بخمس سنين، واضربوهم عليها عشر سنين
Dr. Khalifa: Is it 7 or 10? A man: 10
Dr. Khalifa: 'Ashr (عشر)?
A man: 10
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. 10 years. "Beat them, beat them when they reach 10."
A woman: So, they can beat you back. A woman: Yes.
A woman: Yeah.
A woman: When you look, I mean, if you look at, like, the kids here, I mean look at they, I mean, they look like they're enjoying Praying and they know they should but...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, they are. A woman: They don't know anything. They don't any (unintelligible)
A woman: I mean, that's all they know. They have to be there. it's natural for them.
A woman: like eating, drinking, going to the bathroom. A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You see how Hany runs to the Prayer? I didn't even give him 10.
Dr. Khalifa: Go get the candy. I forgot.
Dr. Khalifa: He's not doing it for the candy.
A woman: He's not doing it for the candy. For God.
Dr. Khalifa: [24:54] Say, "Obey GOD, and obey the messenger." If they refuse, then he is responsible for his obligations, and you are responsible for your obligations. If you obey him, you will be guided. The sole duty of the messenger is to deliver (the message).
The criterion of obeying the messenger is whatever he's saying must be in the Quran, must be backed up by what God is saying.
If it is not in the Quran, it's your obligation to disobey. Actually, in this same Sura, it says that.
So, the reason God is saying
[24:54] ... "Obey GOD, and obey the messenger." ...
Dr. Khalifa: is that because the messenger conveys the word of God, the message.
Parivash: Ok. Excuse me, Rashad. Somebody asked me about this. "What happens if, ok, we believe in Rashad is the messenger of God, but what happens if he is human as (unintelligible)?"
Parivash: And Alhamdu Lillah, I showed them you did and I explained "ok, if you're right and he is mistake, he is responsible for his answer to God." Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Parivash: "But you have, God said 'you have to obey him' either, if you think maybe, maybe he's...", you know.
Parivash: This is (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, if, if on the Day of Judgement say "what did you believe that the age of 40 is this or that (unintelligible). I believe you're messenger, then that will be an excuse. If, if I'm making a mistake, it will be my responsibility.
A woman: At the last line, it says,
[24:54] ... The sole duty of the messenger is to deliver (the message).
A man: So, you can realize easily who is the real messenger. Parivash: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. God's Promise Kings and Queens on Earth.
One of the most important verses in the Quran.
[24:55] GOD promises ...
which means it's done.
[24:55] ... those among you who believe and lead a righteous life, that He will make them sovereigns on earth, as He did for those before them, and will establish for them the religion He has chosen for them, and will substitute peace and security for them in place of fear. All this because they worship Me alone without setting up any idols beside Me. Those who disbelieve after this are the truly wicked.
Dr. Khalifa: What more can we say?
Audience: (unintelligible) A woman: God promises (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The believers have no fear and no grief. No fear. No grief.
A woman: Can I ask one more question? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: What's exactly righteous life? Because you did it last time in my place but I was with my kids.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, righteous, it means abide by the Quran's commandments and prohibitions.
Dr. Khalifa: It's very simple. And God gave us a very simple, very simple things to do.
A woman: At the first of the Sura (unintelligible), 3 categories of people (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, righteous. Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) A woman: Yeah.
A man: (unintelligible) A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: I guess one who becomes a believer. A woman: Yes.
A man: We would appreciate this course. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: How does one know (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: If there is no more doubt.
A man: No more doubt.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, you're a believer.
Dr. Khalifa: The difference between a Muslim and a Mu'min is the doubt. That's only that.
So, a Muslim is a person who believes in God, believes in the Hereafter, leads a righteous life,
does all the commandments and the prohibitions, but there are lingering doubts once in a while.
When all these doubts are gone, then the person is a believer, a Mu'min.
Sura 49.
Found it. The Muslim And The Mu'min.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 49:11. Ok.
A man: Yeah, You were discussing insurance before this.
You were saying there's, there's always something like, as you said, the lingering doubts.
When are you, when are you protected, when you're a Muslim or when you're Mu'min?
A man: So, you're sure that God will protect you if you don't have insurance.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. It takes, it takes a believer.
It takes a person, a person.
When we do the Prayer, yes.
When we come back to the Prayer "give me the candy."
When you say "Allahu Akbar", then pray.
Dr. Khalifa: You thought you were the smartest one, right?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He's okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, it takes, takes a believer to know that he or she has insurance of God.
"I'm a solid believer."
By the way, God tells us how to attain this certainty.
It's at the end of Sura 15. It's the last verse.
Sura 15, which is 99.
You add that to the number of the Sura, you have 114.
It makes it very important.
Page 267.
It says,
[15:99] ... worship your Lord, in order to attain certainty.*
So, a Muslim will do the five Prayers, fast the month of Ramadan, and so on, and this is how he or she will attain certainty.
All the doubts will be gone.
Also, one of the functions of the miracle of Quran is to establish certainty, remove all doubts.
So, a person who understands the miracle of Quran will have no doubts.
A person: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm? Right.
A man: That's a (unintelligible). They just understand the miracle. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And all doubt is... Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: This is at 74:31, where it says "to remove all doubt from the hearts of the believers, even the Christians and Jews."
A man: Now, I understand from headlines of your Muslim Perspective that you have some new discovery.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: You have a headline that says (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And the point, the important thing is whether they understand it or not.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: If they understand, they will know.
Behrouz: I think the only way to remind a disbeliever is that to have (unintelligible) all the time.
We said some good things, we believe you, then they changed their minds, because exactly like I was before.
I was Muslim, I prayed occasionally, I can read the Quran, so after a while, I forgot everything.
So, yes. That's exactly the only thing. We believe you are the messenger, you are true really.
Behrouz: But they have to practice so that (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, exactly.
Parivash: Rashad, could you please explain the, this, the word Mu'min (مومن) and Iman (ایمان) that the Quran says "don't say you are Muslim, you are..."
Dr. Khalifa: "Don't say you're a Mu'min (مومن), say you're a..." until all doubts are gone. The difference between a Muslim (مسلم) and a Mu'min (مومن) is the doubt.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Doubt.
Dr. Khalifa: There is doubt, the person is not a Mu'min (مومن) yet.
A woman: Rashad, is that right that as soon as we attain...
Dr. Khalifa: But that's not, excuse me, that's not bad.
Dr. Khalifa: It just means that the person is inching towards being a believer.
It's, it's like we're born babies, first.
You can't be born an adult.
You have to be a baby first.
This concept of born again Christian is true, you know.
You can be a born again Muslim.
But when you're born again, you're a baby.
Dr. Khalifa: And you have to accept the fact that you must grow and develop slowly until you attain that stage of adulthood or maturity, and certainty.
Parivash: We have a, Rashad, we have a discussion, Rashad, that's they said
Okay, there's a lot of people, they say "we are believers, believing in God."
Parivash: But they are not Muslim. Believing in God. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, God says "don't say that."
A woman: No, they aren't Mu'min (مومن). They are not Mu'min (مومن).
A man: They believe but they haven't submitted.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: That's the difference.
A woman: They believe in God, but...
Dr. Khalifa: Isn't there a word stronger than believe (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Certain.
A woman: Certain. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But it's not, it's not. applied, it's not used in the language.
Dr. Khalifa: Like a person can say "I believe" and say "I'm certain." A woman: I know.
A man: I'm certain. I know. Dr. Khalifa: I know?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: I trust God. I trust and I'm certain.
A woman: (unintelligible) A man: I'm certain. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Beyond the benefit of the doubt. Dr. Khalifa: I have to invent new vocabulary.
A woman: Yes.
Parivash: We could, yeah, because when we say "believe, don't say I am Muslim", they will, and they say "we are believers, believe, we're believing in God." But they are not believing in the Hereafter. They are not believers.
A man: But I think the submit, the word "submit" should distinguish that.
A man: Because if they say "we believe", then we can question them "have you submitted to the Quran, also?" Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: We have no, when, when they say "we have submitted", that means that they should be following the Quran. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I guess when a, when a person says "I submit", this means I applied to admit, to be admitted to first grade.
A man: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I'm gonna sit and be a student.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And when you go to a class, you are admitted into a class, we sit there and we listen to the teacher.
So, we submit to God being our teacher.
Then, we read the textbook.
See what it says.
Who's making noise over there?
Dr. Khalifa: Who's the noisy kid?
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: So, as I see, Rashad, I think as we get certainty, I think certainty, then we are a Mu'min (مومن). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Right.
A woman: And at this case, are tests will be finished. And Everything will be (unintelligible) and good.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes, I think... A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: Yeah, I think, I think certainty. Yes, Rashad?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, everything will be alright. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Even if you go apply for a job and you don't get it, you'll understand.
A woman: Oh, Ok. Oh, I see what you're saying. Ok. I see what you're saying.
A woman: I mean, Rashad, when, you know, I, but right now, Alhamdu Lillah, I (unintelligible) my child.
A woman: But when I the (unintelligible)
A woman: So, I opened the Quran, Alhamdu Lillah, God says in one of the verses, it was saying that, like, (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: That's exactly what's happening.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: It's just like your dream.
Dr. Khalifa: To answer your question, Azar, read 55 again.
Dr. Khalifa: 55.
Azar: At the same Sura 24, verse 55? Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Azar: [24:55] GOD promises those among you who believe and lead a righteous life, that He will make them ...
Dr. Khalifa: Sovereigns.
Azar: Sovereigns Dr. Khalifa: It means kings and queens.
Azar: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Just one word for it, instead of two words.
Azar: [24:55] ... as He did for those before them, and will establish for them the religion He has chosen for them, and will substitute peace and security for them in place of fear. All this because they worship Me alone without setting up any idols beside Me. ...
Dr. Khalifa: Does this answer your question? Azar: ... Those ...
Azar: Pardon?
Dr. Khalifa: Does this answer your question? Azar: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: [24:55] ... substitute peace and security ... in place of fear. ...
Dr. Khalifa: Everything will be alright.
A woman: What about Sura 22, verse 15, which says "Happiness Now, and Forever"? We let go everything and just depend on God alone.
A woman: And it doesn't matter what happens, it doesn't bother you.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: You just accept it the way God wants it.
Dr. Khalifa: Unless you wanna follow some other translation, then you hang yourself.
A woman: Yeah.
A woman: Yeah, of course.
A woman: Yeah, (unintelligible) A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: It's true.
Dr. Khalifa: They hang themselves.
A man: (unintelligible) A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: 22:15 is the verse that was translated unanimously in all the other translations as
"If you don't believe that God can help you in this world and forever, hang yourself."
Dr. Khalifa: Really?
Parivash: Yes, yes.
A woman: What?
Dr. Khalifa: I thought you knew that.
A woman: Yeah, I know.
A woman: Cause, well...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so you have to read it for us then.
A woman: What? Huh? A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: Thank God, I never saw that.
Dr. Khalifa: Really?
A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: Let me see. Oh, you like this, don't you?
Edip: There are, there are several different interpretations on this. All of them funny from each other.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: The other one says "let him go to sky and open a hole from the sky and look at his face."
Dr. Khalifa: Must be Ibn Kathir.
Edip: Their duty. Their duty.
Dr. Khalifa: Their duty, yes. Well, this is a contemporary Mufasir (Interpreter).
A woman: Funny.
Dr. Khalifa: He's more sophisticated.
A woman: This is hilarious.
Behrouz: This is a model.
A woman: But this is really good to show people how it's really been mistranslated.
A woman: This is hilarious.
Edip: This is wonderful.
A woman: "If any think that God will not help him, his apostle, in this world and the hereafter, let him stretch out a rope to the ceiling and cut himself off."
A woman: "Then let him see whether his plan will remove that which enrages him."
A woman: After, after his death?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, now, let us say you're a very careful person who wants to follow the Quran to the letter.
A woman: I'm dead. I'm dead.
A woman: Wait, I'm finished. Dr. Khalifa: Just...
Dr. Khalifa: Just read it carefully and see what he's trying to tell you and do it. Because it's important. This is God's message to you.
A woman: I'll be dead. I will have committed suicide.
Dr. Khalifa: That's alright. Yes. A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: Good God.
Edip: Rashad, what did I do? You know I criticized them.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: And they were okay, all Turkish (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: How dare you?
Edip: Because in this way, after my critique, I told them, to these translators, I said
Edip: "if you think that you are right, now I challenge you that you hate yourself and don't think either you are right or not."
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. A woman: Now, can I read yours?
A woman: Can I read yours? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
[22:15] If anyone thinks that GOD cannot support him in this life and in the Hereafter, then let him turn completely to (his Creator in) heaven, and sever (the dependency on anyone else). He will then see that this plan eliminates anything that bothers him.
A woman: I mean, that is so clear. And it's real.
Dr. Khalifa: That's, that's the message in the Quran.
Edip: In the context, you read from the words, words above and all the context is this. A woman: Yeah, it is in context.
A woman: This is out of context.
A woman: And it makes no sense at all.
A woman: Not at all.
A man: Because they've brought, brought their idol, Muhammad, in there.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Yes, yeah, they put Muhammad in there. Edip: You know there is no mention of Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no... It has nothing to do with Muhammad. Edip: There's no Muhammad in there.
A woman: It has nothing to do with Muhammad at all. Edip: (unintelligible)
A woman: Because even the Ayat before is talking about God admitting the believers and leading them into, you know, they're ready for a righteous life. It has nothing to do with Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, well, we'll go back to work and we'll see you, IN SHAA ALLAH, for Salat Al-'Asr.
A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I did.
Dr. Khalifa: I was, I was vice president of the Sunni mosque.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, one day, I told them not to follow Hadith of Sunah. So, here I found that sign saying "For sale", so, and I asked and I bought it.
Behrouz: What (unintelligible) job, for example, the (unintelligible).
We're doing it, we're doing it (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: We expanded it. Their mosque was only up to here.
Behrouz: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And then we added this part. So, we keep expanding.
Dr. Khalifa: And I think we need, we need a new expansion soon, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: It's getting there.
Dr. Khalifa: Last Friday, we didn't find a place to sit down.
A woman: You're going to see people walking.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm pretty sure, IN SHAA ALLAH, we'll take the whole block. This whole block and we'll build a mosque.
Audience: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: We are. Edip: We go and... Rashad, we go and invade the other mosques. There's a new one.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I checked it out and the direction of Qibla is wrong. So, I said "well, we'll not take it."
Edip: Do you think it is wrong?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Their Qibla is, they're looking northeast.
Edip: uh-uh. Really? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They designed the whole thing looking at northeast.
A woman: Over there? Dr. Khalfia: Yes.
A man: Toward the magnetic north.
Dr. Khalifa: Either that or we can just, you know, if we can move it, IN SHAA ALLAH, we'll do it.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) the land (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Where?
Dr. Khalifa: Here in Tucson?
A man: Yes. Somewhere.
Dr. Khalifa: It's not expensive here. A man: (unintelligible) buy land, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: Besides, nothing is expensive for God.
Dr. Khalifa: Like Carl Sagan says "God has billions and billions..."
A man: I thought (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he mimics Carl Sagan.
Dr. Khalifa: "Billions." A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: Which mosque is the one on the Freeway?
Dr. Khalifa: Ahmadiyya. Ahmadiyya mosque.
A woman: How many mosques are there in Tucson?
Dr. Khalifa: How many? Three. A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's Ahmadiyya. How many mosques?
A woman: I thought it would be 1.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, 3 mosques. I thought "how many Ahmadiyya's are?"
A woman: How many are there?
Dr. Khalifa: There are also 3 Ahmadiyyas.
Dr. Khalifa: 2 of them enforce it. Actually, this is a surgeon. An anesthetist, not a surgeon,
who was making a lot of money and meets Ahmadiyya and it's good for his IRS taxes.
A man: Taxes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, he built a mosque and he put in two guys to take care of it from Pakistan.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there are three of them here.
Parivash: Rashad, last night, somebody asked me "if I'm in the street and I have to do my Prayer and the mosque that does not belong to any god. And can I go there and Pray?" I said "No," Dr. Khalifa: No.
Parivash: "you cannot." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because there is a direct commandment saying "don't", in a very strong way.
(9:108) لَا تَقُمْ فِيهِ أَبَدًۭا
Edip: This mosque must be the worst place that you go there. You cannot find any place there to go there. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
A woman: He said he had to go to the bathroom. Bathroom.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Edip: Because if you go there and worship, you accept the places they worship there. Dr. Khalifa: what they're doing. Parivash: Yeah, exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. A woman: 9:108
Dr. Khalifa: It's actually a house of Satan. Will you go in a house of Satan to pray?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Because in Sura 9, really the commandment is very strong. I used to be not sure. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, when I read this verse over and over, it says,
(9:108) لَا تَقُمْ فِيهِ أَبَدًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: "Do not ever..."
A woman: Yeah, I see it. [9:108] You shall never pray in such a mosque. Dr. Khalifa: Do not never ever pray...
Parivash: I thought, and you know, they didn't believe, some of them. Mã Shã Allãh. I just opened this verses. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: It's very clear. Nobody can doubt it. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Vicky: And about their kids that we were talking, I have a sign, IN SHAA ALLAH, like, God is my witness that I'm not lying.
Vicky: The first time I met Dr. Khalifa, Makan was maybe three or four months.
Vicky: And at that age, the kid doesn't talk. And he said three or four times, Allah, Allah.
And then, I forgot all about that.
Last time that Dr. Khalifa came to our place, and he had lunch with us.
And then, the first group left to Parivash's place.
And I went with my kids and Muhammad to Parivash's house. In the way, we were so excited that Muhammad started saying "Allah, Allah."
Like he was trying Zikr while he was driving.
And God is my witness, I'm not lying.
He tried. And he tried in my arms. He knows it.
Vicky: He pushed and said "Allah, Allah." Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
Vicky: And then, I didn't say anything.
I was afraid I tell Muhammad that, then Muhammad say "Oh, Vicky, you know, don't say it."
I was just thinking. And then, he turned at me and said "did you hear?"
Vicky: You know, he's trying very hard.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And he tries with... Dr. Khalifa: Translation.
A woman: Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Mã Shã Allãh.
Vicky: I think that's why, like, the kids should be like...
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, they start very early. I was asking Mahdi. I was not joking. One week.
Then it turns out, in their mother's womb, they're listening to the Quran. They're Baroni kids.
A woman: Yes. Mã Shã Allãh. A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They wanted Parivash's recording.
A woman: Ilahi (my God) Dr. Khalifa: Ilahi (my God). Yes.
A woman: Ilahi (my God) all the time.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: Jahan was, Jahan was saying when he was saying Zikr, in his sleep "Allah, Allah."
Dr. Khalifa: In his sleep? A woman: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This is amazing. Francisco sleeps here and then I go to wake him up for Fajr.
Here is a Chinese-Mexican guy. Okay?
He wakes up and he said "La Elaha Ella Allah. Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah. What's going on here?"
It's Francisco, yes.
I wake him up "it's Fajr prayer." But it's really fantastic (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Because you don't think when you're getting up from your sleep. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Your brain is still asleep. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, when they interrogate prisoners, they want to hear the truth, they wake him up and ask him immediately a question.
"Where is your army camping?"
"Three blocks from here. Wait, what did I say?!"
A man: No control. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Parivash: Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: You cannot manipulate their brain.
Parivash: One day my brother was in the army, and he came home and he was really, he wanted me to go to one of my friends, a neighbor, to bring him to another city because it was very difficult.
And he was asleep at the room, and I went to my neighbor, and he said "okay, bring him to talk with me maybe I..."
And I went and I said...